Preliminary Guide to the Joshua Lawrence Horne Papers, 1917-1974
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Joshua Lawrence Horne papers 1917-1974
Horne, Joshua Lawrence
38.7 linear feet Extent: 46,000 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00577
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Joshua Lawrence Horne Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1974-1976.
Biographical Note
President of the Rocky Mount Publishing Company, publisher of the Evening telegram and Sunday telegram of Rocky Mount, chairman of the State Board of Conservation and Development, member of the State Advertising Campaign. Duke University Trustee, 1934-1965. Died March 15, 1974.
Collection Overview
The Joshua Lawrence Horne papers comprise primarily general correspondence (1918-1974, bulk 1959-1971), including many letters from Horne's secretary during Horne's annual visit to Orlando, Fla., with general news about Rocky Mount and Horne's publishing enterprise; letters from H.E.C. Bryant; and correspondence with representatives in the N.C. General Assembly and the U.S. Congress. The office files primarily concern the N.C. Dept. of Conservation and Development and the Associated Press.
The collection also includes papers (1941-1971) concerning the Southern Newspaper Publishers Association, as well as material about Duke University, including correspondence relating to the Board of Trustees, the Office of Alumni Affairs, the Athletic Dept., and the Office of the President; and material from 1968 concerning the protests from African-Americans which resulted in the occupation of the Allen Building.
Other materials in the collection relate to Piedmont Aviation Co.; the Birdseye Farming and Management Co.; the Carolina Motor Co.; the Rocky Mount-Wilson Airport Authority; the Methodist Church; the N.C. Conference of the Methodist Church; and the First Methodist Church of Rocky Mount; as well as addresses and writings (1963-1970), clippings (1950-1974), printed material (1952-1971), miscellany (1917-1970), and photographs.
Further information about the contents of the collection is available in the repository. Contact Research Services staff.
Subject Headings
Horne, Joshua Lawrence; Bryant, H. E. C.(Henry Edward Cowan), b. 1873; Southern Newspaper Publishers Association; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University. Office of Alumni Affairs; Duke University. Athletic Dept; Duke University. Office of the President; Duke University -- History; Piedmont Aviation Co; Birdseye Farming and Management Co; Carolina Motor Co; Rocky Mount-Wilson Airport Authority; United Methodist Church (U.S.). North Carolina Conference; First Methodist Church (Rocky Mount, N.C.); North Carolina. Dept. of Conservation and Development; Associated Press; Publishers and publishing -- North Carolina; Rocky Mount (N.C.) -- History
Contents of Collection
- Accessions June 28, 1974 and May 17, 1976
  - Correspondence, 1918-1958 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1961 Jan.-Sept. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1961 Oct.-1962 July (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1962 Aug.-1963 Jan. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1963 Feb.-Aug. (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1965 Apr.-Aug. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1966 Feb.-July (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1965 Sept.-1966 Jan. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1963 Sept.-1964 Feb. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1964 Mar.-Sept. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1964 Oct.-1965 Mar. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1967 Aug.-Nov. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1968 May-July (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1967 Dec.-1968 Apr. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1966 Aug.-Dec. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1967 May-July (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1967 Jan.-Apr. (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, 1968 Aug.-Sept. (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1968 Oct.-1969 Jan. (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, 1969 Feb.-May (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1969 June-Sept.15 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1969 Sept. 16-1970 Feb. (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1970 Mar.-July 15 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, 1970 July 16-Nov. (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1970 Dec.-1974 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 27)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box 28)
  - Pictures, undated (Box 28)
  - Volumes, undated (Box 28)
  - Rocky Mount Wilson Airport Authority Papers, undated (Box 29)
  - Addresses and Writings, undated (Box 30)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 30)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box 30)
  - Printed Material, undated (Box 30)
  - Duke University Papers, undated (Box 31)
  - Methodist Church Papers, undated (Box 32)
  - Financial Papers, 1936-1969 (Box 33)
  - Legal Papers, 1916-1970 (Box 33)
  - Rocky Mount Publishing Co. Papers, undated (Box 33)
  - Southern Newspaper Publishers Association Papers, 1941-1971 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, 1931 July-1937 July (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Aug.-Dec. and undated (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 May (Box 38)
  - Correspondence, 1941 June-1943 Dec. (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 40)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Jan.-Aug. (Box 41)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Sept. (Box 42)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Oct.-Dec. (Box 43)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Jan.-Mar. (Box 44)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Apr.-May (Box 45)
  - Correspondence, 1948 June-Aug. (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Sept.-Oct. (Box 47)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Nov.-Dec. (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Sept.-Dec. (Box 49)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box 50)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 51)
  - Financial Papers, undated (Box 51)
  - Legal Papers, undated (Box 51)
  - Pictures, undated (Box 51)
  - Printed Material, undated (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Jan.-Mar. (Box 52)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Apr.-May (Box 53)
  - Correspondence, 1949 June-Aug. (Box 54)
  - A-Ads, undated (Box 55)
  - Agencies-ANPA, 1939-1940 (Box 56)
  - ANPA, 1941-1946 (Box 57)
  - Bailey-Duke U, undated (Box 58)
  - Eastman-Scott, 1937-1938,type="inclusive>1940-1943 (Box 59)
  - Eastman-Scott, 1944-1949 and undated (Box 60)
  - Eastman-Scott, 1937-1938type="inclusive>1940-1943 (Box 61)
  - G-L, undated (Box 62)
  - M-N, undated (Box 63)
  - P-Roberts, 1936-1937 (Box 64)
  - Roberts, 1938-1941 and undated (Box 65)
  - S-Sharp, 1937-1938 (Box 66)
  - Sharp, 1946-1949 and undated (Box 67)
  - Solicitations, 1940-1941, 1946-1947 and undated (Box 67)
  - Solicitations, 1948-1949 and undated (Box 68)
  - Wildlife, undated (Box 68)
  - Conservation and Development Ad-E, undated (Box 69)
  - Conservation and Development F-H, undated (Box 70)
  - Conservation and Development N-W, undated (Box 71)
  - Conservation and Development Volumes, undated (Box 72)
  - Conservation and Development A-E, undated (Box 73)
  - Conservation and Development F-Sharp, undated (Box 74)
  - Conservation and Develepment Sharp-Z, undated (Box 75)
  - Conservation and Development, undated (Box 76)
  - Conservation and Development, undated (Box 77)
  - Conservation and Development, undated (Box 78)
  - The Associated Press Papers, 1937-1940 May (Box 79)
  - The Associated Press Papers, 1940 June-1944 (Box 80)
  - The Associated Press Papers, 1945-1947 (Box 81)
  - Associated Press Board Members, undated (Box 82)
  - Associated Press Guild, undated (Box 82)
  - Associated Press Meeting, undated (Box 82)
  - Congratulatory, undated (Box 82)
  - REA, undated (Box 83)
  - ANPA, 1947-1948 and undated (Box 84)
  - Photograph, N.C. Press Association members, Charlotte, N.C., 1921 Jan. 3-6 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Newspaper clipping, Ed Oldham, Once Sentinel Editor, Spread Twin-City Fame, Winston-Salem Journal and Sentinel, 1929 Dec. 1 (Opaperfolder 1)